# Vasilis Sarris

He / Him / His | Pittsburgh, PA, USA | v.sarris@pitt.edu | github.com/sarrisv | linkedin.com/in/vesarris

### SUMMARY

PhD student in Computer Science at the University of Pittsburgh, focused on database management systems (DBMS), specifically optimizing join algorithms for cloud environments. This specialization provides a strong understanding of the entire data processing pipeline, from remote data ingestion to query optimization / execution in disaggregate environments.

#### **EDUCATION**

University of Pittsburgh	Pittsburgh, PA, USA
PhD, Computer Science	Aug 2023 — Present
• Advisor: Panos Chrysanthis	
University of Pittsburgh	Pittsburgh, PA, USA
MSc, Computer Science	Aug 2021 — Apr 2023
University of Pittsburgh	Pittsburgh, PA, USA
BSc, Computer Science	Jan 2019 — Apr 2022

### EXPERIENCE

Dec 2020 — Present Researcher

Advanced Data Management Technologies Lab

Pittsburgh, PA, USA

- Extended work in Indoor-Outdoor Navigation by creating and implementing multiple novel path finding algorithms.
- Wrote and published multiple first-author papers on these novel algorithms.

Researcher Jan 2021 — Apr 2021 Kovashka Lab Pittsburgh, PA, USA

- Explored the effects of pre-processing the input of object recognition models (ResNet, AlexNet, etc.) in such a way that was more akin to the visual cortex.
- Preformed domain generalization benchmarks on these models using the standard and modified inputs.

Apr 2019 — Dec 2020 Research Assistant Pittsburgh, PA, USA

Learning Imaging & Family Experience Lab

- Developed a robust, user-friendly, graph-based fMRI analysis pipeline for the lab's PhD students.
- Developed multiple web-based tasks for large-scale, NIH-funded psychology studies.

#### Visiting English Teacher

Jul 2019 — Jul 2020

□□□□□ (Dong'ao Elementary)

Nan'ao, Yilan, Taiwan

• Taught English to 100+ elementary school children, grades 1st-5th.

## SELECTED PUBLICATIONS

- [1] V. E. Sarris, C. P. Sweeney, S. M. Linton, B. T. Nixon, P. K. Chrysanthis, and C. Costa, "GIO.G: A Generator for Indoor-Outdoor Graphs to Simulate and Analyze Urban Environments," in 25th IEEE International Conference on Mobile Data Management, MDM 2024, Brussels, Belgium, June 24-27, 2024, IEEE, 2024, pp. 243-246. doi: 10.1109/ MDM61037.2024.00050.
- [2] V. E. Sarris, P. K. Chrysanthis, and C. Costa, "Recommending the Least Congested Indoor-Outdoor Paths without Ignoring Time," in Proceedings of the 18th International Symposium on Spatial and Temporal Data, SSTD 2023, Calgary, AB, Canada, August 23-25, 2023, ACM, 2023, pp. 121-130. doi: 10.1145/3609956.3609969.

## SKILLS / SELECTED COURSEWORK

- Programming Languages: C, C++, Java, Python, Scala
- Development Tools: CMake, GDB/LLDB, Git, Google Test, Intel TBB, Make, perf
- Courses (Grad): Design & Analysis of Algorithms, Adv. Database Systems (@ CMU), Seminars on AI, CV, & IoT
- Courses (Undegrad): Algorithms & Data Structures, Database Management Systems, Graph Theory